ANDY CHEN

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate holder. Rich experience in full-stack software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team.

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

EXPERIENCE

<u>Blockchain Node Service Inc.</u>, San Francisco — Founder and Project Lead Developer July 2018 - PRESENT

- Leveraged Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distribute stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decrease responding time by 50%.
- Developed a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Lead Engineer* turned *Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

- Co-authored whitepaper and designed and developed the whole end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month.
- Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Launched ERC20 VentureCoin(VCN) token and released a 3-month crowd-sale in November 2017.

Bodhi Project, San Mateo— *Software Engineer* May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Refactored the whole React UI library from redux to mobX architecture in 4
 weeks and successfully initiated the migration from electron-based to
 browser-based DApp which ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2
 times.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the dev.
- Built the prototype for ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.

Yeah Education Group, Berkeley — *Chief Technical Officer* Dec. 2015 - April 2017

• Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: **Node**, **Golang**, **Python**, RoR, PHP, Swift

Front-End: HTML/SCSS, lavascript,

React/Redux/MobX, Webpack, RWD

Backend: RESTful, GraphQL, Express, NoSQL, SQL, Nextjs, SSR, SEO, JWT

DevOps: npm, **Docker/K8S**, TravisCI, AWS SAA

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Vechain/thorify, update documentation and suggest [#8 closed] new thorify features

amazingandyyy/mern-stac k, open source my mern stack boilerplate repo and gained 14 forks and participants

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update
and improve testing
environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

 The software-based solution successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

<u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Software Engineer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned 95% satisfaction rate from clients.

EDUCATION

<u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Startup Hero* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Grow <u>venode</u> project into <u>BNS</u> and graduated at top 3 as "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day, completed Hero Training Program and is nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper

<u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental).

Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

PROIECTS

<u>Leptin</u> — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and Built a whole cryptocurrency in Nodejs with leveraging the power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain implementing Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

Etherbrite — An Eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register and check-in.

VRPlayer — A video player built with ReactVR and openGL

Built this video player on the fist of ReactVR's launch, with a focus on the interaction details of user experience in virtual reality.

HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - **1st place of Uber Challenge** [2016] for building <u>Teleport</u>, an advertisement site that magically delivers customers to your door.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall**[2015] for building Connect, a radio player controlled by a gesture controller, Myo.

MENTORSHIP/GLOG

Distributed system Salon authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web development, smart contract, DevOps and software design topics.

DIDX/Vechain Blockchain Community Group on Github |

initiative virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland

Reactathon, 2017 Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization